

Dexter Crago

Full Stack Software Developer

Personal Website

dexter18crago@gmail.com

in LinkedIn



GitHub

Hello! I'm a full stack software developer with experience building 30+ projects from scratch and doing contract work for Outlier AI. Please feel free to check out my personal website 🗷 to see some of my work, learn more about me, and find out how I can start adding value to your team right away. I look forward to hearing from you soon!

Professional Experience

Outlier, Software Engineer - Contract 🗷

Jun 2024 – present

- Working on multiple projects evaluating the quality of AI-generated code based on accuracy, efficiency, maintainability, readability, etc.
- Developing robust solutions to coding problems
- Coding to high functional and efficiency standards
- Testing and debugging coding solutions
- Training others through a Slack channel

Stevensville High School, *Science Teacher*

Jan 2023 – Apr 2023

- Managed 100+ students across a variety of subjects
- Developed new teaching strategies and approaches
- Maintained an organized environment
- Descalated tense situations with students and coworkers when necessary

Montana Club, Server

Jun 2015 - Mar 2021

- Increased sales from \$500 to \$1000/day in one year
- Trusted with closing out registers containing \$1000+
- Trained junior co-workers

Youth for Christ, *Youth Worker*

Jun 2018 – Jun 2020

- Successfully started and operated a weekly lunch time program at a local high school
- Collaborated with diverse teams of 2 20 people from multiple background and organizations
- Found new methods of engaging student participation in after-school programs

Education

Full Stack Software Engineering, The Odin Project

Aug 2023 - May 2024

- Created 30+ projects from scratch
- · Responsive frontends with HTML, CSS, JS, and React
- Secure backends with Node.js and Express.js
- MongoDB databases managed with Mongoose ODM
- Jest testing and PassportJS authentication
- Git version control and JSON data transfer.
- Creating and consuming REST APIs
- Fundamental data structures and algorithms
- Agile software development workflow
- Writing clean, efficient, and maintainable code that follows industry best practices and coding standards

Bachelor of Science, Montana State University

Aug 2018 - May 2023

- Secondary Education Broadfield Science
- Strong critical thinking and analysis skills
- Able to easily break down large problems
- Great at communicating complex technical concepts to both technical and non-technical audiences
- Using a testing mindset to pinpoint issues
- Brainstorming creative solutions to a problem

</> Skills

CSS3 • Debugging • Express.js • Git •

HTML5 • ES5+ JavaScript • Jest • JSON •

JWT • MongoDB • Mongoose ODM • Node.js •

NoSQL • Passport.js • Professionalism •

React.js • REST APIs • VS Code • Webpack